# VÍTOR TEIXEIRA

### USER EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONAL

I'm a User Experience Professional with a passion for solving problems with smart and simple user-centered design. Passionate about life and technology, my goal is to make sure the latter does not get in the way of the former, but instead makes it better.

### > WORK EXPERIENCE

SAPO PORTUGAL TELECOM
Apr 2013 - Present

### USER EXPERIENCE & QUALITY ASSURANCE

Conducted the user-centered design process of some of SAPO's main web projects.

Designed and tested wireframes and prototypes with users and stakeholders.

Designed user studies' protocols and question naires.  $\label{eq:constraint}$ 

Performed heuristic evaluations of SAPO's and partner's products. Ensured Accessibility, SEO, and Performance guidelines were adopted. Conducted card sorting and usability test sessions with users. Developed and reviewed the results of A/B and Multivariate tests.

MAIN PROJECTS: SAPO Mag | SAPO Biz | SAPO Blogs | SAPO Vídeos | SAPO Promos | SAPO UX

MLDC
MICROSOFT PORTUGAL
Jan 2011 - Mar 2013

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER / RESEARCHER

Researched on natural user interaction and Human-computer interaction. Interviewed elderly users to gather requirements for the development of a multimodal digital personal assistant.

Specified, prototyped, tested and developed desktop, mobile, and web projects.

 $Conducted\ usability\ studies\ with\ users,\ both\ elderly\ and\ mobility\ -impaired.$ 

MAIN PROJECTS: Living Usability Lab | AAL4ALL | PaeLife | Living Home Center Prototype

OPTIMUS SONAECOM Jun 2006 - Apr 2010

#### SERVICES SUPPORT AGENT

Over-the-phone technical support and troubleshooting.

Technical complaints management for Optimus (Mobile telephony), Clix (Home ISP) and Kanguru (Mobile ISP).

## > EDUCATION

DEGREE & MASTER OF SCIENCE 2006 - 2011

## TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SCIENCE

ISCTE - University Institute of Lisbon (ISCTE-IUL)

Dissertation on the impact, in the elderly population, of multimodal graphical user interfaces for interacting with communication services and social networks.

Dissertation PDF (3.6 MB)

Birth

Phone (+351) 968784447

Email

Website vteixeira com

### LinkedIn

inkedin.com/in/vsdteixeira

#### Skillset

User research

Wireframing

Prototyping

Information Architecture

Interaction design

Usability testing

Heuristic evaluation

A/B testing

Quality assurance

### Toolkit

Sketch

Omnigraffle

HTML/CSS

Selenium IDE

Visual Website Optimizei

Brain, Pen and Paper

### Hobbies

Talking about UX
Movies & TV Shows
Hardboiled Literature
DiY / Handywork
Barbecuing

### Languages

PORTUGUESE

**ENGLISH** 

**SPANISH** 

